

ChanderKant Katyayan

Sr. Web Developer

9310260721



chanderkant@hcit.in



LinkedIn.com/in/chanderkant -katyayan-a643a336

Address 🕠



H.No. C-4/4, Gali No. 7, Arjun Mohalla, Near BabuRam Chowk, Maujpur, North East Delhi 110053

My Latest **Updated Resume** can be found at:

http://chanderkant.hcit.in

Date : ___/___

Place: Delhi

[Chander Kant Katyayan]

To, Hiring Manager

Dear Madam/Sir,

I would like to apply for the web developer desig in your organisation

I have experience designing ecommerce, service oriented, portfolio, custom needs websites and custom web app solutions. While much of my experience has been in the education sector, I have been working as an IT teacher/trainer for past 12+ years. I have very good hands on experience of Business Management and Development too. For past 4 years I have dedicated my efforts to honing my skills as a web designer/developer and has delivered 100+ successful solutions to a variety of requirements independently and as a team.

My responsibilities included the design and development of the solution, Client interaction, Team organisation, and Business Development [Marketing and Lead conversion].

Experience has taught me how to build strong relationships with all departments at an organization. I have the ability to work within a team as well as cross-team. I can work as a web designer/developer to resolve technical issues and implement technical enhancements, work with the development department to implement design and functional enhancements, and monitor site statistics and conduct search engine optimization.

At present I'am working as Sr. PHP developer cum CTO at AutoKartz Internet Private Limited, DLF Tower, Moti Nagar Delhi. My current take home salary is Rs. 50k per month.

Please find enclosed/attached my CV. I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerelu.

ChanderKant Katyayan

ChanderKant Katyayan



9310260721



chanderkant@hcit.in



EXPERTISE

Web Development
IT Applications
Crypto Dashboard
Core PHP and Frameworks
Database Designing
Team Handling
Acquiring New Trends
Domain and Hosting
Management
ERP and CRM

Pro. Qualifications

- "O" Level from DOEACC in 1998.
- "A" Level from DOEACC in 2001.
- One year Diploma in DTP and Designing from CGT Computers Brahmpuri
- Language and Soft Skills training from Hero MindMine South Ex. in 2002
- 3 days full day resident corporate training for PD and Communication skills by NIE [A subsidiary of NIIT] at Sainik Farms in 2003

ChanderKant Katyayan

Sr. Web Developer

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a versatile web professional working in the industry for past 5+ years. While most of my work has been on Core PHP and Wordpress, I have an excellent hands-on experience of dozens of other Web and Programming platforms. I am looking for a position which give me a chance to grow, and, provide financial freedom for my family

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Web Developer

AutoKartz Internet P. Ltd. - Punjabi Bagh - [Dec. 2016 - Aug. 2018]

At AutoKartz I have delivered a variety of tech solutions for different platforms along with the upgrade and maintenance of the existing site code. Apart from the development I was responsible for my team, tech hiring, client interaction and delivery. Following are some project I have delivered:

- Crypto currency site and dashboard for EraSwapToken.io
- Android and iOS App for AutoKartz.in
- YoMechanic.com : an Auto News Portal and Garage Listing solution
- Responsible for the maintenance and upgrade of existing site https://www.AutoKartz.com written in Laravel 5
- Development of a CRM solution for the business todo automation of the presale and post-sale routine along with content management on the frontsite
- Development of https://AkBeta.AutoKartz.com : new and improved AutoKartz Portal from scratch in Yii2 (Under Development)
- Development of https://www.TradeKartz.com A
 Multivendor E-commerce Market Place for Auto Parts
- Added several features to the site like Ajax Search, Dynamic Filters
- Integrated PayTM, PayUBiz on site
- Creating a Mini-site system for nationwide service partners
- Creating a Lead Management System for enquiry capture and conversion

Sr. Web Developer

The Last Hope P. Ltd. - West Delhi - [Dec 2015 - Dec 2016]

One of the most fun place to work. I have worked here as TL Tech Team managing a small team of 4 person in the Web Development department. Following are summary of my work at TLH:

SKILLS

HTML, DHTML, CSS JavaScript, jQuery FabricJS, Charts FoxPro, Clipper, Xbase Database Programming C/C++, Cobol Core & Advance PHP Python, Laravel Yii2, MVC **API** Development Mongo DB, Crypto cPanel, WHM, AWS DNS, Mail, SMS **API** Integration Payment Gateways AJAX, MySQL Web Designing Web Development SEO, SMO

Web Site Management
Wordpress, Joomla
Drupal, E-Commerce
Carting, CMS, CRM
Custom Development
PageMaker, Photoshop
Corel Draw, Tally, Office

Hobbies & Interests

Teaching
Reading
Coding
Designing
Movies
Singing
Listening to Songs
Spending time with my
kids and family

EXPERIENCE continued

Sr. Web Developer

The Last Hope P. Ltd. - West Delhi - [Dec 2015 - Dec 2016]

- Responsible for all the ongoing projects supervision
- Completed 20+ website and development projects as Main Designer/Developer
- Delivered 6+ custom development projects
- Responsible for client liaising
- Setup a CRM for the company's internal working
- At many times doubles as the Marketing/Customer Relation Manager for major clients/corporates
- Recently completed projects includes:
 - o http://supportmeglobal.com/
 - o http://www.chaploos.com/
 - o http://sharadadvertising.com/
 - o http://www.ajda.in/
 - o http://warranteed.in/
 - o http://www.thelasthope.in/

Web Developer

PradSoft Pvt. Ltd. - Vasundhara, Gzb. - [May 2015 - Nov 2015]

- Web Design and Development head.
- Involved in the incorporation of the business
- Done Some marketing and started initial 3 projects
- Completed business website

Web Trainer

IANT Sahibabad [2011 - 2015]

- Web Design and Development trainer for the ADWD course.
- Modular trainer for HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL and AJAX

Web Developer

PradSoft Pvt. Ltd. - Vasundhara, Gzb. - [May 2015 - Nov 2015]

- Web Design and Development head.
- Involved in the incorporation of the business
- Done Some marketing and started initial 3 projects
- Completed business website

Center Head cum Sr. Trainer

HCIT - Sahibabad - [2006 - 2011]

- Designing various courses and writing study notes for them.
- Preparing and conducting various examinations.
- Conducting classes and teachers training for various topics.
- Designing, Developing and managing the website of HCIT with SEO /SMO and content writing

My Introduction

I am a Resident Indian national, Hindu [Brahmin] by birth and teacher by nature. My father is retired from Filmi Duniya [Hindi Film Monthly] as Circulation Manager. I am married since 2001, have a loving wife and two joyful kids. Currently I reside at the following address with my family

Address 🛈

110053

H.No. C-4/4, Gali No. 7, Arjun Mohalla, Near BabuRam Chowk, Maujpur, North East Delhi

My Latest Updated Resume can be found at:

http://chanderkant.hcit.in

Place: Delhi

[Chander Kant Katyayan]

EXPERIENCE continued

Sr. Trainer cum Center Coordinator

CCMT - East Delhi - [2004 - 2006]

- Designing various courses and writing study notes for them.
- Preparing and conducting various examinations.
- Conducting classes and teachers training for various topics.

School Coordinator cum Main Faculty

NIIT@Schools - East Delhi - [2003 - 2004]

- Conducting and supervising computer education in various schools.
- Main faculty at Saraswati Bal Mandi, Geeta Colony.
- Organising summer camps at various schools in East Delhi.

Computer Faculty for CBSE XII Standard

GLTSBM - Ashram, Delhi - [2001 - 2002]

• CBSE's 085 [Informatics Practice] and 083 [Programming in 'C'] teaching with practical to XI and XII standard.

Database Developer

Freelance - SOHO - [1999 - 2004]

Worked as a part time freelance xBase developer completed various small projects for various clients includes [USO, St. Marry School, MCS, ShreeJi Insurance, ACS, Ratan Publishing House etc.]

Owner cum Business Manager

ShreeLaxmi Web Service - SOHO - [2006 - till now]

A home based part time business dealing in Domain Registeration, Web Hosting, Web Designing and Development and SEO/SMO, Bulk-SMS and Email Marketing Service. Completed 50+ Design / Development projects in past years.

Education

Academic Qualification

Certification	Board / Univ.	School / Collage	From	Till
B. Com.	DU	Shyam Lal Shahdara	1998	2001
XII Comp. Sci.	CBSE	R.A.V. Nai Sarak	1997	1998
X [Gen.]	CBSE	R.A.V.	1995	1996